# LEON ALERI MPAKA

Location: London 07552712985 – Leon.mpaka@yahoo.com

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Resilient Assistant Project Manager & BMS Rep (Business management systems) with over 2 years of experience planning and managing small projects and providing support and project coordination to large & complex global projects requiring collaboration with a number of business functions. Strong dedication to exceeding performance levels through effective implementation planning, strategizing and execution. I have a strong desire to revamp processes and procedures where I see shortfalls and increase efficiency and product/project control.

#### SKILLS

- Logistics management
- Project management
- Project coordination & administration
- Contract management
- Research
- Stakeholder Management
- Python (basic)
- Hypothesis testing, A/B testing, statistical significance (Basic)
- SQL
- Power BI (Basic)

- Account management
- Risk management processes and analysis/Due Diligence
- Microsoft Office
- Budgeting
- Document control
- Account reconciliation
- Operations Management
- Python for Data analysis (Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib)
- Microsoft Excel

## **WORK HISTORY**

10/2016 to current

# **Events Project Manager (Part time)**

AIMA Events – London, London

- Sold out 20 consecutive events with over 25000 attendees in a 3-year period. Collaborating on events with the likes of Virgin Music and Metropolis music.
- Carry out data analysis using SQL to optimise event marketing, promotion and social media optimisation of the DLT Brunch brand.
- Analysis and reporting from project planning through to delivery, using data to drive decision making, identify risks and opportunities to optimize the business.
- Project management from inception to delivery of events, event budget forecasting and planning, venue scoping, talent booking and logistics management.

# 01/2017 to 06/2019 Assistant Project Manager

#### Mott MacDonald - London, London

- Tasked with Project coordination, supporting Project Managers and Directors on a number of project related tasks such as Financial management of projects valued from £1 million to £41 million with over 50 team members globally, invoice reconciliation, contract management, logistics management, budget forecasting.
- Complex document control procedures, including budget, contract, invoice tracking and updating RAID logs.
- Extensive stakeholder management with senior management, global team members, clients, and sub consultants to ensure effective project communication.
- Leading change management of due diligence processes within the international health division. Trained, coached and mentored staff during process as well as act as a super user regularly providing advice on best practice.
- Performed KYC and AML checks including on-boarding, credit checks and consulting and providing recommendations to senior management on decision making.
- Overseeing BMS (Business Management Systems) Compliance on 8 global projects worth over £1 million each & 5 bid proposals simultaneously. Exceeded project control & compliance KPIs ensuring Project management processes are followed and standards are met to ISO 14001 and 9001 certification standard.

## 04/2016 to 01/2017 **Property Manager**

# Abby Properties – London, London

- Accomplish financial goals i.e. securing an average of 8 rental agreements per month on minimum and report periodically on financial performance. Securing 30% higher than average new rental agreements on a regular basis.
- Keep up to date with current market trends conducting detailed analysis, identify new opportunities and Design business plans for assigned properties to suit customers' needs.
- Effective stakeholder management. Communicated with owners, residents and onsite associates to deliver excellent service and issue resolution.
- Provided support on several building maintenance projects, meeting strict deadlines.
  Providing support to the project manager.

#### 01/2013 to 04/2016 **Operations Manager**

Afrobeat360 Ltd – London, London

- Built client relationships by acting as the liaison between the customer service and sales teams.
- Created proposals for new and repeat customer business transactions.
- Negotiated prices, terms of sale and service agreements.
- Developed and implemented creative, cost effective programmes which increased client retention rates by 20% compared to the prior year.
- website usage analysis performed, helping identify customer behavioural patterns to maximise website experience. Effective website traffic management and post analysis.

#### **EDUCATION**

2007 A level – Business - C, ICT – C, Sociology - B

**Christ the King Sixth Form College** 

2010 Bachelor of Arts: Business Management

**Kingston University** - Kingston, Surrey

2016 PRINCE2 Foundation Certificate: Project Management

The Knowledge Academy - London

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION \_

Currently event manage & DJ at a brunch/day party part time, attended by 1000+ people per event, named DLT Brunch as an additional source of income, selling over 10,000 tickets in the summer of 2019. I also have an interest in Anime and music, especially Hip hop, R&B and Snake Jazz.